

MECU Mihai-Sorin

Passionate Full-Stack developer searching for a remote job

Over 17 years of experience in domains like Logistics, Stock Exchange market, Finance and Administration, GPS tracking and Fleet Management, Customs Borders scanning.

Enthusiast about Machine Learning and Functional Programming

0040.747.02.01.02

mecumihaisorin@gmail.com

mecu.sorin

in linkedln profile

github

Contact:

Age: 40 Citizenship: Romanian Married, 1 child Cat AB driving license

Current Status

Immediately available - Searching for the next project to be excited about.

Skills

Extensive experience in finding practical working solutions to business problems.

Described as *reliable, friendly, creative, enthusiast* and *efficient*. Having a good grasp of Design Patterns, DDD, BDD and TDD. Characterised by the habit to learn something new with every chance.

Programming Languages

Programming languages polyglot. List of programming languages I would like to use in future projects:

F# (5 years as hobby and 18 months in production)

Elm / Elmlang

Haskell

Python

Go / Golang

C# (13 years in production)

TypeScript (5 years)
JavaScript (8 years)

Education

Deeplearning.ai by Coursera platform

Deep Learning Specialization - Certificate License DKMDM27AJZ9Z

2018

Composed by following courses:

- 1. Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- 2. Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization
- 3. Structuring Machine Learning Projects
- 4. Convolutional Neural Networks
- 5. Sequence Models

Stanford University by Coursera platform

Machine Learning course - Certificate License NNJVA7SM77QV 2016

University of Bucharest - Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science

Master's Degree, Computer Science - Artificial Intelligence 1997 – 2001

Recommendations

I managed Sorin for 18 months while at RealtyShares, and his attention to detail and work ethic were exceptional. He is deeply passionate about F# and Machine Learning / AI concepts and in practice. One event he even stayed up and online past 4am his time to participate in an F# ML hacking session with the team and F# community. Of the many arduous tasks Sorin conquered while on the team, most impressive was the migration of hundreds of thousands of financial documents from one platform to another in under a month of working on it. Fighting through inconsistent data and unreliable identifiers between documents and users, he was able to re-home every single statement. It was a pleasure working with Sorin; I look forward to the next opportunity.

Had the pleasure of working with Sorin for roughly a year. Although he joined as a remote contractor, he quickly became an indispensable member of our team. Very conscientious developer who's scrupulous about testing, domain modeling, and correctness. He wrote many of the core F# libraries at RealtyShares and contributed to several high-profile projects as a team lead. Despite this, he's refreshingly modest and welcoming of constructive criticism. Sorin does exemplary work and is a true practitioner of the craft. No question he elevates any organization's development team, and he integrates exceptionally well as a remote team member.

Experience

Beside professional experience, as hobby, implemented various utility projects, gadgets (started with ATMEL microcontrollers, later Arduino) and mobile (F#, Fable, Elm, Java, Cordova, Ionic, Golang, Canopy, Selenium, Docker). I'm having a lot of fun doing various ML projects using TensorFlow and Keras.

Live-coding in F# on YouTube: Watch Sorin live-coding in F# on YouTube

IT Consultant at RealtyShares Inc.

1 year 6 months (December 2016 – May 2018) Referees: *Daniel Driscoll* and *Tracy Gonzalez* (Worked remotely the entire period)

Activity short summary:

- » Created a critical back-end layer (40k F# loc) for the platform
- » Migrated the functionality from an Orchard CMS to a new solution that we build in-house without any activity interruptions
- As a side project: I held training sessions for teaching F# to my colleagues

Technologies and framework used: F#, Suave, Expecto, Hopac, Paket, Fake, Canopy, C#, LinqToSQL, ASP.Net MVC, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Javascript, React, Redux, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, and others ...

Senior IT Consultant at MB Telecom LTD SRL

1 year 1 month (April 2015 – April 2016) Referee: Andrei Iacobita

Activity short summary:

- » Added new functionalities and enhancements to the code base of an application that is used by the Customs Borders Police
- » Optimized the database queries and removed redundant calls, greatly reducing the response time
- » Augumented the testing platform to ease the code maintenance, fixed the bugs, improved the code coverage
- » Elaborated a tool that cope with data fragmentation, by auto-activation on the dynamic events configured
- · As a side project: programmed a small Arduino device and the associated mobile application.

Technologies and framework used: C#, TSQL, TypeScript, C++, MSSQL, LinqToSQL, ASP.Net MVC, EF, WCF, ASP.Net WebForms, Rx.Net, Azure, RxJS, AngularJs, Ionic, etc..

Solution Developer at SAS Grup

5 years 3 months (September 2009 – November 2014) Referee: *Adrian Dinu* (Worked remotely over 4.5 continuous years)

Activity short summary:

- » Created a complex platform (from the services to the UI, everything except database queries and GPS devices specific logic) that provides fleet management solution as a service (biggest in Romania, that is used by companies like Coca-Cola, Orange, Vel Pitar). Analyzed, provided and presented, in various forms, the data collected by the GPS devices mounted on the cars.
- One of the side-projects was to reverse engineered the API of a personal tracking device, by sniffing the serial communication, to create a configuration application (to remove human errors and to reduce the time needed from 8 minutes to less than 1 minute per device).

Technologies and frameworks used: C#, TypeScript, JavaScript, TSQL, WCF, WPF, WWF, Silverlight, WinForms, ASP.Net WebForms, ASP.Net MVC, Telerik, Unity IOC, OpenLayers, KnockoutJS, AngularJS, OpenstreetMaps, Leaflet, D3.js, SignalR, Rx.Net, T4, SQLite, etc..

Solution Architect and Developer at Rosal Grup SRL

2 years 5 months (April 2007 – August 2009) Referee: Cosmin Oprea

Activity short summary:

- » In a team with other 2 programmers, developed an ERP solution for a group of over 40 firms with different area of activity (street cleaning, trash recycling, electronics manufacturing, tiles manufacturing, i.a.).
- One of the side-projects was an inventory scanning application on Windows Mobile that could operate both on-line and off-line.

Technologies and framework used: C#, JavaScript, TSQL, WinForms, ASP.Net WebForms, MSSQL, MS Reporting Services, Crystal Reports, WS-Security, Windows Mobile, etc..

IT Manager at SSIF Euro Invest Vision SRL

2 years 8 months (September 2004 – April 2007) Referee: Corona Radulescu

Activity short summary:

- » Maintained the solution used by the brokers for trading on the Stock Exchange.
- » Fixed some very subtle bugs inherited in the code base
- » Improved the application data flow between the brokerage house and the Stock Exchange Authorities
- » Added new features and updated the business logic to keep up with the frequent changes of the Stock Exchange regulations.
- As a side-project started the tranzition of the platform (except the accounting application) from Access to Microsoft SQL server.

Technologies used: TSQL, Visual Basic, C#, Access, MSSQL

Solution Developer and IT Administrator at SC Magic Tic-Tac SRL

3 years 2 months (April 2001 – May 2004) Referee: Dan Plosca

Activity short summary:

- » Developed an ERP solution for a firm that provides food distribution and logistic services.
- As a high note created a driver for a POS in FoxPro, to improve the speed of sales.

Hobbies

Aikido and Chess - to keep a healthy body: "Mens sana in corpore sano"



Thank you for your patience!

Let me reward your attention with a joke: What does a redneck say before he gets injured? "Watch this!"